adjustable weight benches are such an
important piece of equipment because you
have so many different angles that you
can work with if you're looking to add a
new adjustable bench but you're getting
lost and all the options that are
available we came to a good place my
friend because i have two
awesome weight benches here with me
today the rogue adjustable bench 3.0 and
the rep fitness ab5000 i can't wait
to get started on this one today so
let's get right to it
[Music]
what is up everybody it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
comparison review
ready to go for y'all today this time
i've got the rogue adjustable bench 3.0
and the ab5000 from rep fitness in this
video i'm going to compare these two
weight benches and help you decide which
one needs to be in your home gym
but before i get going we've reviewed a
ton of weight benches on barbin.com and
if you want to browse our best list just
go ahead and search barbind best weight
benches and you can find out for
yourself which ones we like the best
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the
similarities between these two weight
benches and i'm going to state the
obvious first they're adjustable meaning
you have a lot more added versatility to
your workouts they're both made from 11
gauge steel which is the highest quality
you could ask for when it comes to home
gym equipment
thankfully they both have a handle and a
set of wheels to make it easy to move
them around your home space because they
weigh around 125 pounds which is
pretty heavy and i'll dig into price in
just a minute don't you worry but
they're available for nearly the same
price all right now let's talk about
those differences so these are both
adjustable as i've mentioned a couple
times now but it's a little different in
how they adjust so
the rogue ab 3.0 is a ladder style
adjustment while
the rep fitness ab5000 is a pop pin
adjustment the rogue ab 3.0 has
10 different back pad adjustments while
the ab5000 has seven different back pad
adjustments but
ab5000 has five different seat pad
adjustments while the rogue av 3.0 has
three different seat adjustments for you
to use so my favorite thing about the
ab5000 is that it has this zero gap
mechanism right here meaning there's
literally zero gap no matter what
position you have the seat and the
backpad you don't have to deal with that
while the rogue av 3.0 does have a gap
right here it's only a one inch gap and
it's not like that's terrible or
anything but it's definitely still there
the rogue ab 3.0 also has a thinner
front foot design than the ab5000 does
right here so you might have you know a
better chance of getting your feet set
up more comfortably with the 3.0 than
you would with the ab5000
and i also think that this handle design
right here on the 3.0 is a little bit
easier to grab than it is with the
ab5000 so the av5000 can actually be
transformed into an fid bench which
stands for flat incline and decline if
you were in fact to purchase the
optional leg roller attachment it's
going to pop in up here at the back side
of this bench that's going to allow you
to do that the back pad is also an inch
wider than it is with the ab 3.0 you can
also swap it out for an even wider pad
if you wanted to
both of those things are not available
with the rogue ab 3.0 and the last
difference here is while you can
definitely stand this upright to store
it you know the ab5000 really isn't
meant for that you might actually mess
up the top part of your back pad right
there so
can't really do that all the time but
that is the case with the ab 3.0 because
it does in fact have a vertical stand
built into it so you can store it how i
have it right now
okay so let's talk about money now i
mentioned both of these weight benches
are available for about the same price
but let's start with the rogue ab 3.0 so
the version that we have right here is
listed right around six hundred dollars
but
if you want you can opt in for stainless
steel adjustment rails instead of the
black ones that i have right here that's
going to be an additional 100 or so
once you tack on your shipping and your
taxes you're looking at spending around
700 maybe 800 you know if you were to
get those stainless steel rails now
you can opt in for a premium textured
foam padding instead of this vinyl
padding right here it's not a wider pad
as i mentioned but you can do that if
you were to do it it's going to be an
additional 160
so potentially you could be spending
around 900 maybe a thousand dollars on
this weight bench okay so with the rep
ab5000 it also comes in two different
prices the one we have right here along
with the other colored options that i'll
talk about in just a minute starts
around 600 bucks if you were to go for
the clear-cut option it's going to start
around 680
now if you do want to transform this
into an fid bench you want to get that
leg roller attachment it's going to cost
you about 110
and that wider back pad that i mentioned
that's a shade under 100
so let's say you went with one of the
colored options got that leg roller
attachment and that wider back pad
you'll be spending around eight hundred
dollars but if you went with the clear
coat and got both of those attachments
you'll be spending around 900
now obviously both of these weight
benches are pretty expensive but when
you consider the fact that they're both
made from 11 gauge steel which is
premium quality
kind of makes sense why you're paying a
premium price tag now
let's say you don't care about the type
of steel that is used on your weight
bench you can definitely find some out
there that are much cheaper that could
suit you
just fine but remember those probably
don't have a weight capacity that's
anywhere near both of these right here
which is right around a thousand pounds
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with both of these weight benches i'm
gonna kick this off with the ab 3.0
this bad boy weighs a hefty 125 pounds
it's made from 11 gauge steel which is
professional quality it's once again the
highest grade steel
you could ask for your home gym
equipment to be made from
the vinyl padding right here is pretty
firm so you're going to get some good
support as you're going to do a bench
press but it's not too firm to where
it's uncomfortable when you're laying on
it the back pad is also 11 inches wide i
understand if that's not wide enough for
some people you know once again
unfortunately you cannot swap it out
it'd be nice if there was some variety
but unfortunately can't do that it's a
little over four and a half feet long
and including this rear foot right here
it's a little over two feet wide okay so
let's transition to the ab5000 from rep
fitness once again this also weighs
right around 125 pounds and it's also
made from 11 gauge steel which i don't
know if i need to keep telling you all
this at this point but the highest grade
quality you could ask for it to be no
questions asked
the padding right here it's also firm
comfortable it's made from a non-slip
vinyl so as you start to get pretty
sweaty during your workouts you're going
to get some nice traction you're going
to stay nice and secure and in terms of
footprint it's right around eight square
feet
now in terms of features let's kick this
off with the front foot i personally
love it doesn't take up a whole lot of
room you have plenty of space for your
feet to go on either side of it you're
going to get that optimal foot drive for
your bench press shoulder press really
whatever it is this thing's not going to
get in the way so that's really nice
this gap right here one inch gap you
know some of the adjustments actually
eliminate that gap completely so that's
really nice i think rogue did a really
good job with that it's kind of hard to
avoid that gap unless you know like rep
has that zero gap mechanism but
this is a pretty good job right here you
do have laser cut degree markings for
your back pad as well as your seat pad
it's really helpful just to make sure
you hit that right angle for whatever
lift you're deciding to do
there's rubber underneath the front and
the back feet it's going to add to the
stability keep it from toppling over on
you and that's obviously really nice as
you go to do some step ups or bulgarian
split squats you know really whatever
you're doing it's not going to topple
over the handle and the wheels are going
to make it super easy for you to move it
around because once again it weighs 125
pounds and i really like this built-in
stand right here these take up a lot of
space and that's really nice because
it's gonna you know cut that more than
in half and really just make the most of
your available space and this obviously
comes in red like we have right now it's
also available in blue and black and you
can swap out these black adjustment
rails for stainless steel all right now
let's transition to the av 5000 from rep
fitness if you want to opt in for that
optional leg roller attachment it's
going to snap in right on the back side
right here it's going to allow you to
turn this bench into an fid bench and
you can do some decline bench presses
which really might be a big selling
point for some of y'all watching my
favorite thing about this bench though
is in fact this zero gap mechanism
doesn't matter what angle you have the
back pad or the seat pad at you're not
gonna have to deal with a gap that's
just really cool in my opinion now with
the front foot
compared to the av 3.0 it takes up more
space might not get in the way for
everybody but you know it's good for
some people and in terms of the handle
also not necessarily in the optimal
place
it's one of those things you just kind
of learn to deal with though
obviously i mentioned it before you have
a set of wheels on the back it's going
to make it pretty easy for you to move
this weight bench around and you also
have some laser cut degree markings for
the back pad and the seat pad that way
you can know exactly where everything is
positioned and on top of this metallic
black that we have right here comes in
matte black blue red
and that clear coat option that i
mentioned earlier
[Music]
all right so let's do a quick walk
around with both of these weight benches
i'm going to start with the rogue ab
3.0 so
on the back right here it's your wheels
it's going to make it really easy to
move it around your home gym you also
have your stand right here that's how
you can store it vertically so that's a
really nice feature in my opinion it's
gonna make the most of your space now in
terms of adjusting the back pad it's
pretty easy i like grabbing the pad
itself and you have a handle right here
on either side so just grab both of
those raise up
and you can select from the 10 different
back pad adjustments right there and as
i mentioned
that gap it's gone you don't have to
worry about it it's a really cool
feature in my opinion your handle is
located up front and i really like how
the foot is designed right here it's not
going to get in your way when you're
lifting and that's pretty cool now the
padding right here once again it's
pretty firm but it's also pretty
comfortable at the same time so it's not
like it's going to be you know a
terrible time as you go to lay on it if
we transfer over to the ab5000 let's
compare the feet first
as you can see you know this front foot
definitely sticks out on either side
it's not that bad for me personally but
obviously some of you are different than
me you might not like it the handle is
also a little bit more difficult to
reach because it's a little more hidden
underneath the seat right here while
with the ab 3.0 kind of sticks out in
front of everything but it's not that
bad now
to adjust this seat it also you know it
goes up and down but it also slides from
front to back so you have a little knob
right here just pull down on it and
simply with one hand make it go front to
back now i'm going to hop over really
fast
let's pull this out
if you want to adjust the height
of the seat pull out on this pin right
here
drop it down raise it up
really
whatever you want to do and the same
goes for the back pad you also have a
pin right here you pull it out
it's going to be super easy for you to
adjust it and if i wanted it to go
higher i would just have to slide this
front seat further out now you also have
your set of wheels back here on the back
and you technically could stand the
ab5000 up but
it doesn't have a built-in stand it's
not what it's meant to do so it will be
sitting on this back pad right here
which could essentially mess it up
okay so which of these weight benches
should you go with well honestly at the
end of the day you need to make your
decision based solely on your specific
situation so
let's say you're pretty tight on space
and obviously you want to make the most
of that available space well
ab 3.0 it's probably going to be your
best bet since it can be stored
vertically like i have it right now and
it's going to take up a fraction
of its footprint
let's say you can't stand having a gap
between your back pad and your seat pad
even if it is just a one inch gap
ab5000 is probably going to be the best
bet for that
because it has that zero gap mechanism
adjustments are also going to be a big
factor for a lot of y'all watching but
this might get pretty tricky for some
because av 3.0 has more back pad
adjustments but the ab5000 has more seat
pad adjustment and it can be transformed
into an fid bench with that leg roller
attachment for a whole other style of a
workout
at the end of the day though since
they're priced relatively similar can't
really go wrong with either one of these
weight benches they're both made from 11
gauge steel so it's pretty much a
guarantee they're gonna last you a
lifetime
well y'all that's all i have for today's
comparison over the rogue ab 3.0 and the
rep fitness
ab-5000 these are two awesome weight
benches and honestly you can't go wrong
with either one of these
you just need to make sure you make your
decision based off of what features or
make or break for you specifically some
people are going to want the extra back
pad adjustment ab 3.0 has while others
are going to want to turn the av-5000
into an fid bench for some decline work
thanks for watching y'all i hope this
video helped you out as you're looking
to add a new weight bench to your home
gym
as always stay on the lookout for my
next review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
this comparison just search bar bend
rogue adjustable bench versus rep
adjustable bench that article is going
to pull right up for you you can read
everything that we talked about here
today
i'll see y'all later
[Music]
you